

Software Engineer seeking roles in Software Development, Application Programming, Application Maintenance, Project Management, Requirement Analysis, Solution Architecture, Java, Java Script Angular, Spring Boot, Hibernate, Jersey, Angular Js, Nodejs, Oracle



Current Designation: Software Engineer -Java Total Experience: 4 Year(s) 1 Month(s)

Current Company: CGI Highest Degree: B.Tech/B.E. [Computer Science]

Current Location: Hyderabad / Secunderabad

Pref. Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore, Gurgaon, Hyderabad Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Single/unmarried

Key Skills: Software Engineer, Software Developer, Software Development, Application Programming, Application Maintenance, Project Management, Requirement Analysis, Solution Architecture, Java, Java Script Angular, Spring

Boot, Hibernate, Jersey, Angular Js, Nodejs, Oracle

Verified: Phone Number | Email - id

Last Active: 21-Jan-21 Last Modified: 21-Jan-21

Summary

Having 4 years professional experience building Enterprise applications using java

Hands on experience in developing enterprise applications using Spring, Spring boot, Hibernate ,angular and Web Services Strong experience in creating restful web services

Hands of experience in database to write SQL queries based on user requirements

Java testing framework like junit/mockito

Strong exposure in developing multi threaded applications

Experience in Java design patterns such as Singleton, Factory Design Pattern using Eclipse IDE and intelliJ

Excellent Problem solving ability and Inter-personal Skills, designing the project.

Ability to learn new concepts and new technologies to enhance the skill and company growths.

Having ability to build distributed web applications based on microservices

Hand on experience to develop applications with multi threading and collection in java

Having ability to design UI applications using AngularJS ,CSS,HTML , JavaScript

Work Experience

CGI as Software Engineer -Java

Feb 2019 to Till Date

PROJECT-TRADE360(PRODREL10.2), CUSTOMER- ANZ

Team Size : 12

Technologies & Tools : Java, spring, dataJpa, Hibernate, Rest and Maven, angular

DESCRIPTIONS:

Java Transaction Processing System (JTPS):- The JTPS workflow and rules processing across the entire platform and can be easily configured for a variety of operating models and cost structures. Its Primary capabilities Include:

Transaction processing-Transactions initiated in the CGI Trade360 Portal or by other electronic sources (e.g., SWIFT), or scanned by a bank service center, are automatically sent to the bank's processing center.

Workflow and imaging -Enables the bank to deploy customer service centers where needed and consolidate back-office operations to low-cost locations.

Portal -CGI Trade360's fully-integrated, bank-branded Portal provides access for corporate customers to robust trade processing, reporting, workflow and API driven integration capabilities. It is always synchronized with the TPS.

RESPONSIBILITIES:

Involved in the Analysis, Design, Coding, modification and implementation of user requirements in the applications.

Participating in daily stand up meeting led by our Scrum master.

Documenting all codes changes

Implementing Rest based JAX-RS web services for request processing.

Involved in developing pages using spring MVC

Worked with dataJpa for better performance.

Involved in performing Unit testing.

Used Log4J as a logging API to log message.

ENVIRONMENT:

Java, Jax-RS, spring 4.x, DataJPA, Oracle11g, IntilliJ and JBOSS Server, Maven.

Projects -TRADE360(PRODREL10.3, prodREL 10.4), Clients- BMO, CIBC, ANZ, HFP

Team Size : 10

Technologies & Tools: Java, spring, dataJpa, Hibernate, Web Service (JAX-RS) & Maven

RESPONSIBILITIES:

Involved in the Analysis, Design, Coding, modification and implementation of user requirements in the application.

Participating in daily stand up meeting led by our Scrum master.

Writing code to develop PORTAL and JTPS BASED APPLICATION USING JAVA.

Documenting all codes changes

Virinchi Limited as Java Developer

Dec 2016 to Jan 2019

PROJECT- QFUND (PRODREL10.1), CUSTOMER/client -QC Holding - dates (Dec 2016 to May 2017): -

Team Size : 12

Technologies used : J2EE, struts 2.x, Hibernate, Web Service (JAX-RS), JavaScript, JQuery

DESCRIPTION:

QFund is the global leader in providing IT Solutions to the short-term financial industry in the United States of America . Moreover providing Product which funds Pay day loan, title loan and installment loan for major lenders in the USA. It is a fully configurable software application common to all the lenders. It's also carries loan under writing process. There are major functionalities other than loan procedures like customer registration, e-signature, transactions (loan origination, voids, buyback, refinance etc.), setting up locations and related configurations, setting up security groups, rules and rule values, risk assessment integrating with Third-party Risk Assessment agencies like Tele track, etc., cash management, employee maintenance, report Generation, etc.

Admin Module

CSR Module

LMS Module

RESPONSIBILITIES:

Involved in the Analysis, Design, Coding, modification and implementation of user requirements in the application.

Participating in daily stand up meeting led by our Scrum master.

Involved in performing Unit testing and Used Log4J as a logging API to log message.

ENVIRONMENT:

Struts 2.x, Hibernate 3.x, J2EE, Rest, CVS, Eclipse and JBOSS Server, Maven.

PROJECT- LENDNATION (PRODREL10.2), CUSTOMER- Missouri State - dates (05/2017 TO 01/2019): -

Team Size : 8

Technologies used : AngularJS , Html , JavaScript, jQuery , Rest

DESCRIPTIONS: -

LMS Module

Nacre Software Services as Trainee Developer

Apr 2016 to Aug 2016

Education

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Computer Science) from JNTU College of Engineering, Kakinada in 2015

IT Skills

Skill Name	Version	Last Used	Experience
JAVA			
JavaScript			
Java EE, angular			
JAX-RS			
spring boot			
Hibernate			
Jersey			
AngularJs, NodeJs			
Oracle10g and MySQL, H2			
JBoss, Weblogic			
Tomcat7			
Maven, Ant, CVS, GitLab			
Putty, Winscp, Postman			
Eclipse , Intellij			

Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English				
Hindi				

Affirmative Action

Job Type: Permanent

Physically Challenged: No

Employment Status: Full time

Work Authorization